<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on clayto</title>
    <link>https://clayto.com/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on clayto</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 14:17:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://clayto.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Low-tech Disk Cloning</title>
      <link>https://clayto.com/2019/05/low-tech-disk-cloning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 14:17:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clayto.com/2019/05/low-tech-disk-cloning/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a tale as old as time. A nice laptop. A nearby cold beverage. A sickening splash. Thanks to the solid seals on the Carbon, there was no permanent damage, just a very sticky, nearly unusable keyboard. Rather than clean or replace the keyboard, our support desk opted to issue a new laptop.
That&amp;rsquo;s how I found myself with two identical laptops, one whose SSD had a fully configured OS, and the other with an empty SSD in need of such an OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command Line Bash</title>
      <link>https://clayto.com/2019/02/command-line-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 09:53:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clayto.com/2019/02/command-line-bash/</guid>
      <description>Summary  .float-comp { shape-outside: url(ibm-5150.png); float: right; shape-margin: 16px; margin-right: -16%; max-width: 60%; }  Command Line Bash is a game that challenges you to type in as many commands as you can in 60 seconds.
Play now!  My frequent co-conspirator Jared Sprague and I created Command Line Bash, along with tremendous help from the Command Line Heroes podcast team, open source contributors, and the CLH Discord community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PiTiVi High Quality Rendering</title>
      <link>https://clayto.com/2018/06/pitivi-high-quality-rendering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 10:10:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clayto.com/2018/06/pitivi-high-quality-rendering/</guid>
      <description>My first experience with PiTiVi, eight years ago, was discouraging. Until my dad rediscovered it a few days ago, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t thought of giving it a second chance. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did. I&amp;rsquo;ve been extremely impressed with the improvements. PiTiVi&amp;rsquo;s formerly rough edges have been sanded down, and what remains is an approachable, capable video editor perfectly suited to hobbyist uses.
One of the few remaining rough edges is low-quality defaults when it comes to rendering quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noise/Echo Cancellation in Fedora</title>
      <link>https://clayto.com/2017/10/noise/echo-cancellation-in-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clayto.com/2017/10/noise/echo-cancellation-in-fedora/</guid>
      <description>The Minimic is great. I just received mine last week, and I&amp;rsquo;m loving the ability to join video calls with nice, comfy headphones. It&amp;rsquo;s much better than switching back and forth between headphones and a headset.
The only problem is that, since the minimic is just a wire, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any noise or echo cancellation. And since Fedora doesn&amp;rsquo;t come with that feature enabled by default, the mic was picking up a lot of ambient noise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
